Dwayne Weller

Atlanta, GA 30127 | 404-488-3345 | dpweller85@gmail.com Github | Blog | LinkedIn

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a knowledgeable Full Stack Developer who has had a passion for technological evolution since Windows 95. Experienced in **Ruby on Rails** and **JavaScript Object Oriented** programming with four years' experience as an IT Field Technician, along with two years' experience in **entrepreneurship**, **team building**, and **leadership development**. With my past IT experience, strong skill sets in **problem solving**, **critical thinking**, and **solution seeking**, I strive to help software dependent companies drive continuous technological growth to better the lives of the people they serve.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Git, Ruby, Rails, API, SQL, JavaScript, JSON, JSX, XML, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, NPM, Git | Github, Rspec, Python, Java

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Keepflix Rails - Social Media Application - Github | Demo

A complete Ruby on Rails version of Keepflix that manages data through complex forms and RESTful routes

- Maintained cookies, sessions, and associations using Active-Record on the backend to store logins and encrypted user information in the database
- Leveraged 3rd party Google OAuth to allow multi-provider authentication for users
- Constructed helpers and partials to simplify the HTML and make it more readable for other programmers

Keepflix JS - Single Page Social Media Application - Github | Demo

A rebuild of Keepflix with a Rails backend and JavaScript front end, appending over 50 HTML components

- Implemented JavaScript, HTML, and CSS SPA interfacing with Keepflix Ruby backend API
- Fetch calls handled AJAX and JSON as the communication format
- Utilized Object Oriented JavaScript to encapsulate current user data and display to DOM
- Attached listeners to DOM nodes responds to user interaction and manages CRUD features without page reload

Fortnite Store ReactJS – Single Page Ecommerce Site - Github | Demo

An ecommerce site showcasing Fortnite products built with ReactJS frontend and a Ruby on Rails backend

- Employed react-router to manage RESTful routing between app pages
- Styled using vanilla CSS to customize design to improve user experience
- Built async actions and redux-thunk middleware to send data and receive data from server

EXPERIENCE

AT&T

Powder Springs, GA 10/2015 - 11/2019

- Internet & Entertainment Field Service Wire Technician
 - Provided verbal/written communication to customers, management, team members, and other technical support staff
 to assist and educate with various communication platforms, averaging a weekly caseload of 25 customers.
- Utilized knowledge of networking, satellites, low voltage, bonded pair copper line, fiber optic, and other telecom technologies to install, troubleshoot, and maintain entertainment and information systems while adhering and staying up to date on strict safety standards.

Covidien/Medtronic

Atlanta, GA

Facilities Maintenance Technician

09/2014 - 10/2015

- Performed general building maintenance in warehouse and two neighboring backup facilities, streamlining process of
 prioritizing issues to best utilize the resources and workforce available resulting in reduction in excessive work order
 tickets.
- Supported warehouse management in operational improvements and resolution of facility discrepancies to maintain
 a safe and productive work environment.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Online

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript Certification

03/ 2020 - 12/2020

DeVry University

Decatur, GA

Computer Information Systems

01/2014 - 06/2014

Areas of study include Critical Thinking, Circuitry, Engineering, Word Processing, and Integrated Mathematics